If you are massaging your own horse who is of a fairly calm stoic sort of a nature, there is some real benefits to that.
But there is some disadvantages also.
You can find yourself kind of lulled into a false sense of security.
A calm horse may not let you know as readily as a more sensitive horse when something doesn't feel good to them.
They may be willing to tolerate a lot more from you then a more nervous or flighty horse would.
So that makes it equally important to not take them for granted to pay close attention to what you are doing and close attention to how they are reacting.
A calm horse may show you in much more subtle ways that you need to back off or that you need to move from one area to another.
There maybe less movement of the ears, or less movement of their mouth as they're licking and chewing, they may not sigh and drop their head.
They may just kind of stand there in more or less one position the entire time that you are working on them.
So pay attention to your horse and again know the horse that you are working with and know their likes and dislikes.